Mo PISHDAR

Chatswood, NSW 2067

Phone: 0404786047 | Email: mohpish@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadpishdar/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Mohammad-Pishdar | Portfolio: https://mohammad-pishdar.qithub.io/responsive-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Front end developer trained in the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Sydney, specialised in mobile-first website design leveraging the power of Bootstrap and Pure frameworks to create responsive web page layouts using HTML and CSS while utilising the full power of Google Chrome dev tools for real time debugging. Impeccable JavaScript and jQuery API skills to enhance UX, bringing the UI to life through added functionality. Involved in the design of a fully responsive job search website with dynamically generated content and saved search history utilising HTML, CSS (Pure framework) and JS (jQuery) as the core technologies. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills due to a background in agricultural sciences research and data analysis with expert organisation skills thanks to my experience working in fast-paced hospitality environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development Core Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Pure

JavaScript Frameworks: ¡Query, Node.js, React JS

Web Development Essential Techniques: Version Control (Git), Browser developer tools (Google Chrome dev tools) for testing and debugging, Web Performance (Lighthouse)

PROJECTS

Job Search App | https://github.com/guedesantonio/JOB-SEARCH-APP | https://guedesantonio.github.io/JOB-SEARCH-APP/

- A Job search application that runs in the browser and render results for jobs in the UK dynamically based on the keywords and filters provided by the user while keeping a search history for later use.
- I wrote all the JavaScript code related to the main API used in the app (Adzuna API), all the functionalities of different buttons and check boxes, search history and local storage settings.
- The project involves HTML, CSS (using Pure CSS as the framework), JavaScript (jQuery as the JS library) with a mobile-first approach in design and ajax calls to work with Adzuna job search and Google Books APIs.

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/Mohammad-Pishdar/Weather-Dashboard | https://mohammad-pishdar.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- A weather dashboard that will run in the browser and feature dynamically updated HTML and CSS that uses the Open Weather API to retrieve weather data for cities and stores any persistent data in local storage.
- I wrote the whole app based on a mock-up design and approved user story.
- The project involves HTML, CSS (using Bootstrap as the framework), and JavaScript (jQuery as the JS library) with ajax calls to work with Open Weather API to get the current and forecasted weather data for cities around the world.

Online Quiz | https://github.com/Mohammad-Pishdar/quiz | https://mohammad-pishdar/quiz | https://mohammad-pishdar.github.io/quiz/

- A fully responsive online quiz app featuring multiple choice questions in a timed quiz and rendering a ranked table of high scores that is kept in local storage.
- I wrote the whole app based on an initial design and user story proposal.
- The project involves HTML, CSS (using Bootstrap as the framework), and JavaScript with a mobile-first approach in design and is capable of dynamic rendering and updating of quiz elements while keeping the records in local storage.

EXPERIENCE

Kitchen Assistant 2018 – Present 465 The Avenue Chatswood, NSW

My role is to maintain the kitchen in a presentable fashion through organisation of daily tasks based on immediate priorities, supervising the delivery of supplies, store room stocking, regular maintenance of kitchen appliances, proper communication with kitchen staff to ensure the efficient completion of tasks in a fast-paced environment.

Kitchen Assistant 2016 – 2018 **Ground Espresso** North Sydney, NSW

I was responsible for setting up the café ready for opening, all the food prep, delivery of catering orders, storeroom organisation and supplies delivery management.

Pastry Kitchen Hand 2014 – 2016 Bathers Pavilion Mosman, NSW

I was responsible for all the routine washing and cleaning procedures in pastry kitchen, preparing the necessary plates for all the functions, regular organisation of items in storeroom and weekly maintenance of the machines related to my work.

Research Agronomist 2005 – 2014 Safiabad Agricultural Research Centre Dezful, Iran

My role there was to conduct field research trials designed to answer specific problems of local and national customers, working as a part of the team of quality crops development, statistical analysis of data obtained and preparing the final reports and recommendations.

EDUCATION

The Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW A comprehensive 24-week coding bootcamp for full-stack web development featuring the latest in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, various frameworks and libraries, version control, debugging and testing procedures, database management and server-side technologies.

Intro to Programming Nanodegree: Udacity via Udacity online platform A 4-month program to learn the fundamentals of programming through HTML, CSS and Python to develop thinking and problem-solving habits of a programmer.

Business Analytics Fundamentals: Babson College via Edx online platform A 4-week introduction to business analytics featuring data analysis, sampling and estimation, hypothesis testing, linear models and regression models.

MSc. Of Agronomy: Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran

Bachelor's degree of Agronomy and Plant Breeding: Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran